Guide to the Stanford University, School of Engineering, Audiovisual Material SC1385
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, School of Engineering, Audiovisual Material
1996-2013
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University. School of Engineering
SC1385
2 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research use; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Scope and Contents
Audiovisual material produced by or about the Stanford University School of Engineering. Included are state of the schoool addresses given by the Dean of Engineering, recordings of class lectures, interviews, and programs about research.
Engineering research.; Mechanical engineering -- Study and teaching.; Stanford University. School of Engineering; Stanford University. School of Engineering; Plummer, James D.
- Audiovisual Material
  - State of the School Address - School of Engineering, Jim Plummer, 2008 May 1; 1_01; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Driving Innovation Event Video, 1_02; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Junior/Victorville, 2007 Nov 3; 1_03; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp) (Box 1)
  - E-Day B-1 #6237 - Time of Day Audio Feed Channel 1, 1_04; 1 optical disc(s) (xdcam) (Box 1)
  - Dean's Engineering State of the School Addresss, 2006 May 11; 1_05; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Dr. Plummer Copy 2, 2005 May 10; 1_06; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Engineering State of the School - Clark Aud, 2004 May 18; 1_07; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Dean's State of the School Address, 2002 May 21; 1_08; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - State of the School of Engineering, 2001 May 22; 1_09; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - State of the School, 1997 May 28; 1_10; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - State of the School of Engineering Dean Hennessy, 1999 Mar 10; 1_12; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Stanford University School of Engineering Sunrise Sky News, National Australia, 2006 Mar 29; 1_13; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - The Gates Computer Science Bldg. Dedication and The Future of Computer Science Technology with Bill Gates and Raj Redyy, 1_14; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - William Gates Computer Science Bldg Dedication Ceremony Symposium, 1996 Jan 30; 1_15; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Stanford Racing Team's "Stanley" Trains for the 2005 DARPA Grand Challenge - B-Roll Package - TRT 8 Minutes, 2005 Sep 22; 1_16; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp) (Box 1)
  - Stanford University Prothetics, 2006 Jul 13; 1_17; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp) (Box 1)
  - VAIL Dedication Ceremony - Event Video, 2009 Oct 24; 1_18; 1 videotape(s) (dvcam) (Box 1)
  - The Silicon Genesis Collection: The Microprocessor Chronicles - The History of the Microprocessor, circa 2006; 1_19; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Origins - on beginnings of Hewlett-Packard, circa 2006; 1_20; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - TRIMPIN: The Sound of Invention, circa 2009; 1_21; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Toast - a film by Daniel Hoffman, Porudced by Earth Chronicles, 1_22; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Engineering Day 2011 #6237 "A", circa 2011; 1_23; 1 optical disc(s) (xdcam) (Box 1)
  - Chancellor Merkel Wolkswagon VAIL, 2010 April 15; 1_24; 1 optical disc(s) (xdcam) (Box 1)
  - Peace of Mind: A Film Tribute to William J. Perry, 2007 Oct 17; 1_25; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - James May's Big Ideas: Prog 1 - Come Fly With Me, 2008 Oct 16; 1_26; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Chancellor Angela Merkel Volkswagon Automotive Innovation Lab Stanofrd University, 2010 April 15; 1_27; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Download: The True Story of the Internet: Search, circa 2008; 1_28; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Junior at UC, 1_29; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - School of Engineering State of the School Addresss Jim Plummer, 2008 May 1; 1_30; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - David Orenstein: Stanford Racing Team A Short History Thereof Director's Cut, circa 2005; 1_31; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Fluid Mechanics Seminar: William Frederick Dwanel - From Wooden Ships to Jet Engineers, 2007 April 20; 1_32; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 1)
  - Stanford/Nature - Brain - Computer Interface, 2006 Jul 6; 1_33; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 1)
  - Robocars: Episode 5 - Science Channel, Discovery Studios, 1_34; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Robocars: Episode 6 - Science Channel, Discovery Studios, 1_35; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Robocars: Episode 4 - Science Channel, Discovery Studios, 1_36; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Robocars: Episode 3 - Science Channel, Discovery Studios, 1_37; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Robocars: Episode 2 - Science Channel, Discovery Studios, 1_38; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Robocars: Episode 1 - Science Channel, Discovery Studios, 1_39; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - "Robot Car" CBS Evening News, 2005 Dec 27; 1_40; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - RCC - Stanford Collaboration - Bosch-Gerdes, 1_41; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Great Robot Race - TiVo, 1_42; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Steve Barley - Faculty Courtesy Copy Disk 1 of 1, 2011 Feb 24; 1_43; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Hero Lecture - Faculty Courtesy Copy Disk 1 of 1, 2012 May 22; 1_44; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Hero Lecture - Faculty Courtesy Copy Disk 1 of 1, 2012 April 30; 1_45; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Hero Lecture - Martin Hellman Faculty Courtesy Copy Disk 1 of 1, 2013 Jan 29; 1_46; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Hero Lecture - Craig Barrett Faculty Courtesy Copy Disk 1 of 1, 2012 Nov 1; 1_47; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Hero Lecture - Faculty Courtesy Copy Disk 1 of 1, 2011 Feb 8 - May 12; 1_48; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Center for Teachiing Leaking: "Teaching For Learning" Departmen of English, Professor Jennifer Summit, Hartley Conference Center, 2012 Feb 2; 1_49; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - School of Engineering Terman Awards, 2011 April 9; 1_50; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - EE 212 Dean Plummer Session # 18, 2006 Dec 5; 1_51; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - EE 212 Dean Plummer Session # 10, 2006 Oct 26; 1_52; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Driving Innovation Driving Demos, 1_53; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Gurs Zyklus Presentation, 1_54; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Gurs Zyklus Presentation TRIMPIN - Stanofrd Lively Arts proposed project, circa 2010-2011; 1_55; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - CBS Evening News - "Shelley", 2010 April 30; 1_56; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - BBC News Media Exchange - Cars/Symonds Ten O'Clock News, 2007 Jul 18; 1_57; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - S0E Vignettes, 2007 Jly 31; 1_58; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - S0E Vignettes DV - NTSC + FLV files, 1_59; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - EE 212 Dean Plummer Session # 1, 2006 Sep 26; 1_60; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - EE 212 Dean Plummer Session # 11, 2006 Oct 31; 1_61; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Curis, circa 2007; 2_01; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - BMEC Posters, 2_02; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - BMECS Talby, I, 2_03; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - CS Senior Projects, circa 2008; 2_04; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Engineering Tape #1, 2007 Mar 8; 2_05; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Main Camera Tape #4, 2_06; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Stanford Stanley Comes Home, 2005 Oct 10; 2_07; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Roaming Cam / Tape 4, 2007 Jul 21; 2_08; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Zhenen Pao, 2006 Dec 11; 2_09; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Urban Challene, 2_10; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Pahi AJF-08, 2_11; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Heyneman EOAY 8, 2_12; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - DARPA (1) Opening Ceremony SOT: Sebastian Thrun, Jim Plummer, Race Start/Race Stop, 2007 Nov 3; 2_13; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - EDAY UTILITY (08), 2_14; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Tech Vignettes STUP Class, 2007 Mar 8; 2_15; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - AA Posters (50th Anniversity), circa 2008; 2_16; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Tech Venture Vignettes Tape 3, 2007 Mar 5; 2_17; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - BMRES Talles II, 2_18; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - EXPE '07, circa 2007; 2_19; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Drylen Tape 1, 2_20; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Aaltitude (Lake test), 2_21; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - AJF, circa 2007; 2_22; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Classroom Footage (Schechter), 2007 Nov; 2_23; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Drylen Tupez - Aaltitude (luksviews), 2_24; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Wind tower, 2_25; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - ME 218 "Terman Flotilla", 2_26; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Y2E2 @ Reunion, 2_27; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Dean Plummer, School of Engineering Vignettes, 2007 Jun 4; 2_28; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Stark AJ F08, 2_29; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - School of Engineering "Huang Reception" 4:30pm, 2008 Sep 10; 2_30; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Eaten Jet Engine, 2_31; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - MSE REU 2009, circa 2009; 2_32; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - CS Senior Faire, circa 2009; 2_33; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Paper Biles, 2009 Oct; 2_34; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - ME 382 Spring, circa 2009; 2_35; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - ME 382 Winter, circa 2009; 2_36; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Machine Learning, circa 2009; 2_37; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Dauer REU Students, 2_38; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Students / Lunch / EDAY, 2_39; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Stanford Racing Team Junior B-Roll SD Master TRT 8:15, 2007 Jun 7; 2_40; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - ME REU, circa 2009; 2_41; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Andrlucchi Class ME382, 2_42; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - NQE Tape 2, 2005 Oct; 2_43; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - NQE Tape 1, 2005 Sep; 2_44; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Stanford - Stanley comes home TRT: 1:58, 2005 Oct 10; 2_45; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - EPE Varian Tests, 2_46; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Stanford Racing Team "Junior" B-Roll TRT: 8:10, 2007 Jun 7; 2_47; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - CS 147, 2_48; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Aallitude (Interviews) Dwden Tape 2, 2_49; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - NQE Tape 2, 2005 Oct; 2_50; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - OSO Teacher Program, 2_51; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Coacrem / Feloy, 2_52; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - VAIL Dedication Autonomous Drive Demos, 2009 Oct 24; 2_53; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Chancellor Angela Merkel Volkswagon Automotive Innovation Lab Stanofrd University, 2010 April 15; 2_54; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Iranian Genome Project Russ Altman Daneshjou, 2011 Oct 28; 2_55; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Tech Vignettes STUP interviews, 2007 Mar 8; 2_56; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Main Cam / Tape 1, 2007 Jul 21; 2_57; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Tech Venture Vignettes Tape 2, 2007 Mar 5; 2_58; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Tech Venture Vignettes Interviews: Dean Plummer B-Roll Tape 1, 2007 Mar 5; 2_59; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Roaming Tape 1, 2007 Jul 21; 2_60; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Beat @ E8AY, 2_61; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - School of Engineering State of the School, 2008 May 1; 2_62; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Engineering Tape #2, 2007 Mar 8; 2_63; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - DARPA (2) Tent Area Junior Ends 2nd Course Fininsh - Jr, Victor Tango IUW: Sebastian Thrun, Anya Petrovskaya, Jesse Levinson, Group Photos, Car B-Roll, Victoryville, CA, 2007 Nov 3; 2_64; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Chancellor Angela Merkel Volkswagon Automotive Innovation Lab Stanofrd University, 2010 April 15; 2_65; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - DARPA (3) Closing Ceremony / Awards Post-Awards Presser Sebastian Thrun W/reporters, 2007 Nov 4; 2_66; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - CS 147 Interviews, circa 2009; 2_67; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Anudetres Nilsson Nurskov, 2011 Mar 12; 2_68; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Press Building Demo, 2009 Mar; 2_69; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - EDAY Jim Plummer JB Straybel Hewlett 200, 2008 Jul 12; 2_70; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Ross Evens Xtrucycle, circa 2008; 2_71; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - EDAY Bottle Rockets, 2008 Jul 13; 2_72; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - EDAY (3) Diana Navitysky Steve Rock Bottle Rocked - Rolany Burton Hewtlett 201, 2008 Jul 13; 2_73; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - DARPA 4 Seb. Thaun (2 mins) Victorville, CA, 2_74; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - CS 147 Presentation, circa 2009; 2_75; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Chancellor Angela Merkel Volkswagon Automotive Innovation Lab Stanofrd University, 2010 April 15; 2_76; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - EDAY Oussama Khatib Francois Lonti Hewlett Building, 2008 Jul 12; 2_77; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - CS 147, 2_78; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Heilshorn / EOIY, 2_79; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Tech Venture Vignettes Interview with: Randy Komesau Tom Byeu Tape 4, 2007 Mar 6; 2_80; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - B-Roll Tape #1 #1586, 2007 Jul 8; 2_81; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)
  - Ilan Kruo EDAY, 2_82; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 2)